List<Map<String, dynamic>> ECGPartOneQuestions = [
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead placement provides the best view of the lateral wall of the heart?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead III.', 'Lead aVL.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the normal duration of the PR interval on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      '0.06 - 0.12 seconds.',
      '0.20 - 0.40 seconds.',
      '0.40 - 0.60 seconds.',
      '1.0 - 2.0 seconds.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In which ECG lead would you typically find the R wave tallest?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead aVR.',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A QRS duration of more than _______ seconds is indicative of a bundle branch block.',
    'answers': ['0.06.', '0.12.', '0.20.', '0.40.',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What does a U wave on an ECG represent?',
    'answers': [
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Repolarization of the bundle of His.',
      'Repolarization of Purkinje fibers.',
      'Late repolarization of the ventricles.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'The J-point is the junction between which two waves on an ECG?',
    'answers': ['P and Q.', 'QRS and T.', 'T and U.', 'P and T.',],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a prolonged QT interval?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hyperkalemia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypernatremia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In which ECG lead is the R wave usually smaller than the S wave?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead III.', 'Lead V1.',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common cause of an elevated ST segment on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Myocardial infarction.',
      'Pericarditis.',
      'Bundle branch block.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What does the T wave represent on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In lead aVR, which part of the heart does it predominantly view?',
    'answers': [
      'Inferior wall.',
      'Anterior wall.',
      'Lateral wall.',
      'Septal wall.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which ECG lead is often used to diagnose ventricular infarction?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead aVL.',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by a regular rhythm and a sawtooth pattern of atrial activity?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which coronary artery is often referred to as the "widowmaker" due to its significant role in myocardial infarctions?',
    'answers': [
      'Left anterior descending (LAD).',
      'Left circumflex.',
      'Right coronary artery (RCA).',
      'Posterior descending artery (PDA).',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the most common cause of a peaked T wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
      'Hyperkalemia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'A widened QRS complex can be seen in which condition?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Sinus bradycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which ECG lead is best for detecting myocardial infarctions in the inferior wall of the heart?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead III.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which interval on an ECG represents the time it takes for an impulse to travel from the atria to the ventricles?',
    'answers': ['PR interval.', 'QT interval.', 'ST interval.', 'RR interval.',],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with a heart rate of 150 bpm, no discernible P waves, and a narrow QRS complex. What is the likely diagnosis?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the normal duration of the QT interval when corrected for heart rate (QTc)?',
    'answers': [
      'Less than 0.12 seconds.',
      'Less than 0.20 seconds.',
      'Less than 0.44 seconds.',
      'Less than 1.0 second.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance can cause a prolonged PR interval and prominent U waves on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What does an inverted T wave in leads V1-V3 often indicate?',
    'answers': [
      'Ventricular hypertrophy.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Myocardial infarction in the anterior wall.',
      'Sinus bradycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is positioned at the fifth intercostal space at the midclavicular line?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V4.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which ECG lead is used to view the lateral wall of the left ventricle?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V5.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What does the ST segment represent on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by chaotic and irregular atrial activity with no distinct P waves?',
    'answers': [
      'Ventricular fibrillation.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the P wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which segment of the ECG is normally isoelectric (at baseline)?',
    'answers': ['P segment.', 'PR segment.', 'QRS segment.', 'ST segment.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with a heart rate of 40 bpm, a regular rhythm, and narrow QRS complexes. What is the likely diagnosis?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Sinus bradycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which part of the ECG corresponds to the time it takes for ventricular depolarization?',
    'answers': ['P wave.', 'PR interval.', 'QRS complex.', 'T wave.',],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
];
